# 大家好 今天找兄弟搞一條牛來
Hi everyone! Today I come to my buddy to get a cow.
# 你看 這麼多都是他的
Look! All these belong to him.
# 我去看一下哪條 漂亮一點
I'm gonna see which one, is more pretty.
# 把它牽回去
I'll take it back.
# 先來看一下
I take a look first.
# 你看
Look!
# 上次我賣了一條牛給他
I sold him a cow last time.
# 是哪條啦
Which one is it?
# 有點黃的
It's a bit brown.
# 忘記啦
I can't remember.
# 有點像那一條
It seems to be that one.
# 不像啊 我的很漂亮的
No, it isn't. Mine is very pretty.
# 現在都好像長大啦
I think it has already grown up,
# 不一樣啦
and looks very different now.
# 你看 這一條小牛黑黑的
Look! This calf is rather black.
# 很漂亮的哦
It's so pretty.
# 太小啦
It's too small.
# 怎麼全是公牛 你看
Why are they all male? Look!
# 一條公牛 兩條三條四條
One male, two, three, four
# 全部小牛都是公的
All calves are male.
# 沒有一條母的哦
There's not even one female.
# 這麼奇怪
Strange!
# 全是小公牛
All calves are male.
# 後面還有
There are more behind us.
# 後面還有牛哦
There are some more cows behind us.
# 沒有來哦
They didn't come here.
# 你看
Look!
# 這些都是
These are all,
# 大一點的都是母牛
the larger ones are all female.
# 小的全是公牛
And the small ones are all male.
# 這些公牛都很靚
These bulls are really beautiful.
# 現在還小 兄弟肯定不肯
They are still small. My buddy won't agree,
# 不肯給我的 他要長大一點才給我
won't agree to give me one, not until they become a bit larger.
# 到時候看一看
I'll see by that time.
# 你看 我們本地小黃牛 就是這樣子的
Look! These are exactly our local cattle here.
# 全是吃青草的
They feed only on grass,
# 不肥
and won't get fat.
# 全是瘦肉來的
They have only lean meat.
# 我去兄弟家喝一下茶
I'll have a cup of tea at my buddy's place,
# 順便吃個晚飯再回去
and also a dinner before getting back home.
# 大家好 今天看一下兄弟家的這個魚塘
Hi everyone! Today we'll take a look at my buddy's fish pond.
# 看下有沒有魚 我順便搞一條來吃
Let's see if there are any fish. I can also take one as well.
# 哇 現在看得到哦 好多魚
Wa! I can see the fish now, a lot of them!
# 沒跟兄弟打招呼 兄弟都不在
I didn't call my buddy before coming, and he's not around right now.
# 想抓條魚吃都抓不到
I wanted to catch a fish, but now I can't.
# 看一下還有甚麼東西
Let's see if there are any other things.
# 你看 這個兄弟家的香菇
Look! These are my buddy's shiitake mushrooms.
# 每 我們這邊每家每戶都種啦
Each, every family here grows,
# 種了一點這樣的香菇啊
grows a bit this kind of mushrooms.
# 但是一年的產量 也不是很搞
But the annual yield, is not really that high.
# 一家
A family,
# 一家能
a family can,
# 摘個五六十斤 乾的香菇
can have around 30 kilograms of dried mushrooms.
# 我就沒有
But I have none.
# 所以我們經常去找他們收
That's why we always buy from them.
# 這些被他們摘掉啦
These have all been picked.
# 被兄弟摘掉啦 好多哇
My buddy picked them all. A lot!
# 一棵樹都長那麼多
So many can grow from one single tree.
# 你看 這個香菇
Have a look at this mushroom.
# 它曬了 曬了一下 你看 就裂開啦
It has been under the sun, under the sun for a while. Look! It's cracked.
# 就個就變成了花菇
And now it has become a "hua gu" (shiitake mushroom with pattern).
# 你看 有裂紋的就叫花菇
Look! The cracked ones are called "hua gu",
# 沒裂紋的就叫香菇
while the others are called "xiang gu" (shiitake mushroom with aroma).
# 兄弟不在哦 不好意思摘
I don't feel good to pick them now as my buddy is not around.
# 因為他 我拍摘了他那個 那個 那個小狗哇
Cuz he ah...if I pick them, I'm afraid his, I mean, you know, his doggy,
# 不放過我
won't let me go.
# 還是算了吧
Well, forget it!
# 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
The video ends here.
# 回去啦
Let's go back.